NAVEEN REDDY POGALLA

Pennsylvania, United States

 $+1 (814)-826-9473 \diamond \text{naveenreddypogalla@gmail.com} \diamond \text{linkedin.com/in/naveenreddy} 11/$

OBJECTIVE

Cybersecurity enthusiast with 2 years of experience in Cybersecurity Consulting at EY. Strong communication and leadership skills, offer a diverse skill set with experience in Network and Web Application Penetration Testing, Red Team assessments, and configuration review of Network devices.

EDUCATION

The Pennsylvania State University

University Park, PA

Master of Science - Cybersecurity Analytics and Operations | CGPA: 4.0/4.0

Aug 2023 - Dec 2024

Courses: Penetration Testing, Information Security & Assurance, Cybersecurity Analytics, Network Security and Management, Software Security

Shri Ramdeobaba College of Engineering and Management

Nagpur, India

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science and Engineering | CGPA: 9.74/10

August 2018 - June 2022

Courses: Operating Systems, Database Management Systems, Computer Network, Information Security, Introduction to IoT, Enterprise Systems

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

GRANT THORNTON LLP

June 2024 - Present

Cybersecurity Consulting | Role: Cybersecurity and Privacy Intern

Philadelphia, PA, USA

- Perform technical security testing, including cyber-attack simulations and threat and vulnerability assessments.
- Support cybersecurity assessments consisting of security architecture reviews, system configuration reviews and cloud security evaluations.
- Support cybersecurity incident response readiness activities, including tabletop exercises and evaluations of incident response capabilities.

THE PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY

Jan 2024 - Present

Teaching Assistant

University Park, PA, USA

- Assisting the instructor for two courses EA 876: Architecting Enterprise Security and Risk Analysis and IST 866: Threat Hunting and Offensive Cybersecurity under Dr. Edward J. Glantz.
- Responsible for assisting with in-class activities, specialized software or virtual labs, providing feedback on writing, grading assignments, out-of-class tutoring, and other learning-focused responsibilities.

ERNST & YOUNG Feb 2022 - July 2023

Cybersecurity Consulting | Role: Senior Security Analyst

Mumbai, India

- Conducted security assessment of 97 firewalls for a client during a ransomware attack incident. Provided comprehensive recommendations and delivered results under stringent timelines.
- Executed network Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing (VAPT) and Red Team assessments for Fortune 500 clients to assess the vulnerabilities of Internet, Intranet connected systems, networks, and applications including Windows and Linux.
- Hands-on experience in performing Web Application Security testing. Demonstrated proficiency in OWASP Top 10 vulnerabilities and mitigations, and worked with security testing tools such as NMAP, Nessus, Kali Linux, Wireshark, Burp Suite, Acunetix, and others.
- Conducted comprehensive cloud security audits for leading steel manufacturing company, resulting in identification and mitigation of vulnerabilities, ensuring compliance with industry standards and protecting sensitive data (AWS, GCP, Azure).
- Performed secure Configuration review of Switches, Routers, Firewalls & Endpoints and provided remediation strategies.
- Conducted offensive cyber drills and simulated real-world scenarios to test the effectiveness of security measures and assisted in curating process and procedure documents for incident response playbooks.
- Collaborated on drafting technical proposals to onboard potential clients.
- Awarded for excellence in client delivery on firewall secure configuration activities and leading the network team for incident response.
- Conducted comprehensive configuration review of over 200 network devices, including switches and routers, for one of India's largest tire manufacturers.
- Performed thorough vulnerability assessment and penetration testing at the client's location, utilizing industry-standard tools and techniques. Provided detailed remediation strategies to enhance network security and minimize risk.

HITACHI VANTARA

May 2021 - Aug 2021, Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

Security Engineering | Role: Security Intern

Hyderabad, India

- Collaborated closely with Incident Response and Data Protection teams to evaluate and strengthen network security through hands-on penetration testing and vulnerability assessments.
- Conducted simulated phishing campaigns and spear phishing assessments for Red Team Engagements and client readiness evaluation.

PROJECT WORK EXPERIENCE

BePractical.Tech Feb 2023 - Aug 2023

Domain: Cybersecurity | Role: Content Writer

Nagpur, India

• Collaborated to develop ResNet CNN-based tool for realistic makeup simulation on facial images, altering hair and lip colors. Utilized BiSeNet for feature segmentation (eyes, ears, lips, nose, hair), applying Gaussian blur for smooth color transitions.

• Published a research paper in the International Journal of Health Sciences.

AI Enabled Makeup Tool

Sept 2021 - Jan 2022

Final Year Project | Domain: Machine Learning and Deep Learning | Role: Team Lead

Nagpur, India

• Collaborated to develop ResNet CNN-based tool for realistic makeup simulation on facial images, altering hair and lip colors. Utilized BiSeNet for feature segmentation (eyes, ears, lips, nose, hair), applying Gaussian blur for smooth color transitions.

• Published a research paper in the International Journal of Health Sciences.

Automated Rotoscoping Tool

Feb 2021 - May 2021

Final Year Project | Domain: Machine Learning and Deep Learning | Role: Team Lead

Nagpur, India

• Led a team to develop a PyTorch & OpenCV-based rotoscoping tool, greatly enhancing VFX efficiency by automating frame and video rotoscoping, typically taking days or months manually. Utilized OpenCV and PIL collectively to convert videos into image streams, applying semantic segmentation to categorize pixels into 21 features and color them accordingly.

CERTIFICATIONS

• CompTIA Security+ SY0-701

Certificate

- Certified Cyber Security Analyst (C3SA) Certificate
- Certified AppSec Practitioner (CAP) Certificate
- Certified Network Security Practitioner (CNSP) Certificate
- Fortinet Certified Network Security Associate Certificate
- Python Certification by HackerRank Certificate
- SQL Certification by HackerRank Certificate
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)

SKILLS

Frameworks/Tools Web Application Firewall, FTK, WAFW00F, Nmap, Nessus, Nikto, Packet Tracer,

Cpanel, Autopsy, Git, Github, IAM, Steganography, TCP/IP

Servers Apache 2 Web Server, Nginx Web Server, MySQL Server, Azure, Google Cloud Platform Platforms Linux, Raspbian OS, Windows, MacOS, Oracle VirtualBox, VMware, Raspberry Pi

Languages Python, Bash Scripting Language, SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, JSON

Technical Skills Computer Networks, Penetration Testing and Secure Configuration – Firewall, Switch, Router

Soft Skills Communication, Leadership, Team Player, Client Relationship